## MANSVINI AGGARWAL

#### Software Engineer

♣ +91-9650438090 @ coderspecial@gmail.com ② linkedin.com/in/mansvini

SUMMARY

A problem-solver with 2 years of experience in leading businesses looking to leverage communication skills as a full-stack developer. Coding since the age of 11 with experience in building and deploying projects from scratch using React, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, APIs, Heroku, Netlify, and GitHub. B.tech in Electronics & Communications Engineering.

FIND ME ONLINE



#### Portfolio

mansvini.netlify.app



PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Open Source Contributor

Zero To Mastery Date period Location

A global coding community's open source playground

- Collaborating with community managers and developers from around the world on GitHub and Discord.
- Contributed to ZTM Job Board project using SCSS, HTML & JavaScript.
- Participated in the Animation Nation Hacktober project where the challenge was to use only CSS.

#### Co-founder

Health Blis 12/2019 - 09/2021

A B2B startup in the pharma industry

- Handling end-to-end design and development of websites while regularly updating and maintaining them.
- Testing, deploying and observing content management system to production servers which led to a better User Experience.
- Communicating and collaborating with 200+ stakeholders to build a supply chain which led to a ROI of 16% within 3 months.

#### Core Team Member

Honest Farmer 06/2018 - 03/2019

A zero-waste supply chain to supply produce from farms to customers within 24 hours of harvesting

- Solved the problem of drain water irrigation and food traceability by building the world's fastest 100% traceable food supply chain.
- Working with the core team while managing a group of 6-8 people.
- Brainstorming solutions creatively while handling operations.
- Acquired 200+ customers from a single locality by communication and marketing which converted to 30% regular customers.

## Information Technology (IT) Intern

Oil & Natural Gas Corporation (ONGC) 06/2017 - 07/2017

- Learnt the functioning of ONGC, SAP ERP, and SAP ABAP.
- Built an Online Quiz Software on SAP using the ABAP language.

### **Embedded Systems Intern**

IBM 06/2016 - 07/2016

- Learnt about the practical applications of Embedded Systems.
- Built the project <u>Data monitoring using GSM Module</u> with AVR AT Mega 16, sensors, GSM module and C++.

Delhi, India

**PROJECTS** 

### Smart Brain using ML API

A web app built using React.js as front-end framework, and RESTful API server with Express.js for backend. Stores user information along with hashed passwords securely in a Postgresql database. Deployed on Heroku.

# IOT based portable health monitor

A health monitor which uses sensors, Arduino and C++ to track the vital signs of patients. This app is connected to IOT and can be monitored from anywhere in the world. This is a lifesaver which signals the connected devices in case of an emergency.

EDUCATION

# The Complete Web Developer

Zero to Mastery Academy

10/2021 - 02/2022

## Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech)-Electronics & Communications Engineering (ECE)

Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIPU)

09/2014 - 08/2018

VOLUNTEERING

#### Volunteer

The Art of Living

06/2018 - Ongoing

- Taught about the importance of mental health to 250+ youth.
- Worked with a team and mentors to conduct events for various social causes.
- Continuously organised 10+ workshops for 50+ participants.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

